Hello everyone, let's learn about a series of tools to optimize the shape.
First, let's open the practice file of the fixed needle and the sewing machine.
In this case, we will use the fixed needle and the sewing machine.
Simulate this scarf and wear it on the model.
First, to improve the simulation speed, we can freeze or reactivate the following clothes.
For pieces that have contact with the scarf,
which are the collar and front and back pieces,
you can choose to freeze it with the right button.
Then you can choose the opposite direction with the right button on the piece that has been selected.
The shortcut key is Ctrl-Shift-I.
Then press the Shift key to select the scarf.
For other pieces,
you can choose to set the anti-aggression plate and sewing line.
This will further reduce the calculation and speed up the simulation.
After the preparation is complete, we will deal with the scarf plate.
In order to prevent the scarf from falling directly when simulated,
we need to add a fixed needle to it.
In the first row of the third tool in the left toolbar,
long press to find the fixed needle tool.
Long press to find the fixed needle tool.
You can see that there is a fixed needle case and a fixed needle set tool at the bottom of the grid tool selection.
They are just different ways of selection.
Here we choose the fixed needle case tool.
At this time, the 2D and 3D panels will show a pink grid.
The method of adding a fixed needle is similar to the method of selecting a grid tool.
Just select the frame on the panel.
After the frame selection, there will be a red dot at the top of the grid.
This means that a fixed needle has been added.
At the same time, you can see that the fixed needle selected in the 3D window is orange.
The unselected fixed needle is red.
Now the two sets of fixed needles are selected separately and can be moved separately.
So if you want to add a fixed needle multiple times in a set,
after adding a part of the fixed needle in the frame selection,
you can press Ctrl and Shift to add a selection.
Then the fixed needle selected now is a whole that can be selected and moved together.
Note that the blank area is not possible to cancel the fixed needle selection.
This is different from selecting a grid tool.
If you want to delete the fixed needle, you can select it by pressing Ctrl at the 2D window.
Or on the 3D panel, right-click on the fixed needle and select Delete.
There is a little trick here.
We can add a fixed needle on the line where we need to add a fixed needle.
Just double-click, you can quickly create a row of fixed needles along the line.
We add two rows of fixed needles on the edges of the scarf.
Then in the middle of the scarf, the position of the model in front of you.
Add two rows of fixed needles.
You can refer to the position in the video.
If you accidentally misselect the scarf grid at the back,
you can press Ctrl and select the fixed needle that does not need to be selected.
After adding the fixed needle,
switch the tool to the move tool and turn on the simulation.
Now the goal is to put the two ends of the scarf into the ring on the outside of it.
We can first press the Shift key in the 3D window.
Click on the two rows of fixed needles in front of the model.
Then adjust the position of the ball.
Turn to the side view.
Move them a little bit to the front of the model.
Leave a space for operation.
Pay attention here.
When you move the fixed needle, if you stop the simulation,
then only the part of the grid selected by the fixed needle will move with it.
If you move the fixed needle in the simulation state,
then the selected grid will take other grids on the board.
Then select the fixed needle on the right edge.
Draw the position of the ball.
Press the shortcut key 2 to the front of the model.
Use the position of the ball to move the fixed needle up and move it to the left.
Place it in the top position of the scarf that can pass through the scarf.
Make a trend from top to bottom.
Then right-click to rotate the view.
You can press the Shift key to rotate the view.
Then press the Shift key to rotate the view.
Press the Shift key to rotate the view.
You can feel the obvious stop at the 90-degree rotation angle.
Turn to the side.
If you find that the fixed needle is a little bit too thick,
then we can use the positioning ball to move it forward a little bit
so that it can pass through the scarf smoothly.
This way, we can ensure that
whether it is on the front or on the side,
the fixed needle is in the inner top of the circle of the scarf,
and then use the positioning ball to move the whole thing downward to pass through the scarf.
Be careful not to pull it too tight.
The left side is also operated in the same way.
Because the left side itself is on the inside,
it needs to be rotated from the bottom to the outside,
and then to the circle and to the inside once.
The same can be combined with the view.
Move the fixed needle to the inside of the scarf in the front,
where it can pass through,
and make sure that the side is also in the angle and position where it can pass through smoothly.
After the fixed needle passes through this side,
it needs to be turned to the front and rotated to the outside.
Repeat the process of going inside again.
Here is a small suggestion.
When using the fixed needle adjustment,
it is recommended that you pause frequently.
Then turn on the simulation pause.
You can record the current form,
and avoid going back to the initial simulation state when canceling.
After both sides are worn,
the scarf is now loose.
We can bring the fixed needle reserved in the front closer to the model
to tighten the scarf.
You can press the Shift key to select the fixed needle on both ends of the scarf.
Use the positioning ball to move down together.
After adjusting to the satisfied position,
right-click to delete this part of the fixed needle,
or press the Ctrl and W keys to delete all fixed needles.
In order to make the simulation effect of the scarf more natural and real,
we can reduce the particle diameter of the scarf to 10 mm,
and change the thickness of the scarf to 1 mm,
and then simulate again.
In addition to the way of adding a fixed needle in the frame selection,
we can also add a single-point fixed needle in 3D.
While pressing the W key,
we want to add the position of the fixed needle on the 3D costume.
Right-click on it,
and add a single-point fixed needle.
The position of the fixed needle can also be moved,
and we can start the simulation.
Drag the point of the fixed needle directly to adjust the overall shape.
If you want to delete the fixed needle,
right-click to delete,
or press the W key,
right-click again to delete the fixed needle.
Next, I will introduce the sewing tool.
You can use the sewing tool to adjust the shape of the scarf.
Select the sewing tool.
Click on two points on the board.
You can use either 3D or 2D.
These two selected points
will be connected by a blue curve.
You can switch to the edit sewing tool to check.
You can use the edit sewing tool
to move these two points again.
After opening the simulation,
these two points will be connected and fixed together.
We can use this tool,
to adjust the shape of the scarf,
for example,
adjust the shape of the scarf on the right side.
For adding a good sewing,
you can adjust the position of the two ends of the line,
and then turn on the simulation to adjust the shape.
The sewing tool can also be used to pull the distance of the scarf on both sides.
You can adjust the length of the line.
You can also adjust the length of the line.
The default distance of the two points of the sewing is 0 mm.
Select the curve connected by this line.
In the right-hand attribute editor,
change the length of the line to the appropriate value,
such as 30 to 50 mm.
According to the effect adjustment,
you can add 1 to 2 sets of this type of push.
You can further reduce the diameter of the scarf to 5 mm,
and turn on the simulation.
Finally, double-click to select all the sweater sheets.
Press the Shift key and select all the skirt sheets.
Right-click to select Activate.
Then press the Control key to simulate again,
making the scarf and clothes fit more naturally.
The completed file can be saved by itself.
Next, I will introduce the range drag tool.
Open the practice file.
Usually, when we simulate dragging clothes,
we use the point drag.
Sometimes, it can also be switched to the range drag according to the need.
For example, this one has a twisted strap.
Now the left-hand panel
is connected to the bottom of the right-hand panel.
We need to pull it out
to form an intersectional twist.
One idea is to use the selection grid tool.
Pull out the grid that is connected to the bottom.
There is also a more convenient way,
which is to use the range drag.
First, turn on the simulation.
Move the grid of the fixed needle on the left side of the screen out.
Now we only need to move the grid of the lower part of the left panel to the outside.
In the simulation,
select the move tool as a small grab.
Long press the icon to switch to the range drag.
At this time, the mouse will become two same-center circles.
The inner circle is the core selection area.
The outer circle is the reduction range.
In the set panel that is displayed on the right side,
we can first select the display weight.
It is convenient for us to check the selected area.
In the 3D window,
left-click to drag.
You can move the entire area of the selected green highlight.
Because this area is smaller,
we make the range of the soft selection smaller.
The degree of reduction determines the degree of drag force.
In the surface mode,
the drag effect is only applied to the specified range.
The surface of each selected layer,
In the straight line mode,
you can choose all panels within a certain range of 10 points.
Whether the selected panel and the other layers of the panel are together,
the measurement method is to change back to the surface.
Turn to the side view,
left-click to press the mouse to move outward,
you can easily move the lower part of the panel out.
After dragging out,
remove the fixed pin and simulate again.
The twist is done.
Press and hold again to select the moving tool.
You can switch back to the way of clicking and dragging.
Finally, let's look at the difference between hardening and shape solidification.
Open the practice file,
here are two T-shirts on the ground.
Now the shape is the same.
You can switch to only display the 3D window.
We are on this dress on the left side.
After double-clicking,
right-click to select hardening,
press the shortcut key,
Ctrl plus H.
At this time,
this dress will turn orange.
After opening the simulation,
you can see that the original wrinkles are gone.
All wrinkles have been opened.
Its material will temporarily become like rubber,
very hard.
Hardening is often used to flatten the fabric
or deal with severe curls.
Right-click again to choose to remove hardening.
It will restore the original soft attribute.
Now look at the dress on the right side.
Double-click to select this T-shirt,
and then right-click to select shape solidification.
Press the shortcut key,
Ctrl plus E.
After opening the simulation,
you will find that its wrinkle form has not changed at all.
When we drag it in the simulation state,
it is moving as a whole.
The original wrinkles and shape are firmly fixed,
and it is not easy to change.
You can drag the T-shirt on the left side without solidification to compare.
The solidified clothes are still physically simulated
and can also be moved,
but it always maintains the shape of the solidification at that moment.
Solidification and shape solidification
are used to adjust the needs of various clothing styles.
If you need to check the 3D sample clothes,
you need to use it reasonably.